Marc Chadourne Papers
Marc Chadourne Papers
1928-1956
Chadourne, Marc, 1895-
2.0 linear ft.
Papers of the French author, novelist. Includes manuscripts in French of novels and Chadourne's biography of Restif de la Bretonne.
148891
Biographical History
Marc Chadourne was a French civil servant, author, and novelist, and translator of William Conrad and Henry James.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Marc Chadourne Papers consist of manuscripts in French of Chadourne's writings, including his biography of Restif de la Bretonne and several novels.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically by type and within that alphabetically by title.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- French; Biography; Chadourne, Marc, 1895- Manuscripts.; Restif de la Bretonne, 1734-1806 Biography.; Authors, French.; French literature, 20th century.; Novelists, French.; Drafts (documents); Manuscripts for publication.; Authors.; Novelists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Manuscripts
  - Biographies
    - Restif de la Bretonne
      - No. 1, 1954-1956 (Box 1)
      - No. 2, 1954-1956 (Box 1)
      - No. 3, 1954-1956 (Box 1)
  - Novels
    - Absence
      - No. 1, 1932 (Box 1)
      - No. 2, 1932 (Box 1)
      - No. 3, 1932 (Box 1)
      - No. 4, 1932 (Box 1)
      - No. 5, 1932 (Box 1)
      - Synopsis, 1932; 2 copies, French and English (Box 1)
    - Cécile de la Folie
      - No. 1, 1928-1930 (Box 2)
      - No. 2, 1928-1930 (Box 2)
      - No. 3, 1928-1930 (Box 2)
      - No. 4, 1928-1930 (Box 2)
    - La Clé Perdue, 1944-1947 (Box 2)
    - Dieu Créa d'abord Lilith
      - Drafts A No. 1, 1936-1937 (Box 3)
      - Drafts A No. 2, 1936-1937 (Box 3)
      - Drafts B No. 1, 1936-1937 (Box 3)
      - Drafts B No. 2, 1936-1937 (Box 3)
      - Proofs, 1937 (Box 3)
      - Typed and complete pages 1-35, 1936-1937 (Box 3)
      - Typed and complete pages 36-101, 1936-1937 (Box 3)
    - Le Mal de Coleen (incomplete), 1952 (Box 4)
    - Vasco (incomplete)
      - No. 1, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
      - No. 2, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
      - No. 3, 1924-1927 (Box 4)
  - Synopsis
    - Vaudou, undated (Box 4)
  - Unidentified
    - No. 1, undated (Box 4)
    - No. 2, undated (Box 4)
    - No. 3, undated (Box 4)
    - No. 4, undated (Box 4)